Prakalpha K S

QA Engineer

SUMMARY

An IT professional with 7+ years of successful experience in **Software Testing.** Expertise in Web UI & API Automation and Manual Testing. Have handled projects in various sectors like Insurance, Fleet card, Social Media, E-commerce & Automobile.

EXPERIENCE

IBM: Technical Specialist Jul 2022 - Present

Client:

MBRDI: Involved in Test planning, Test case design, Execution and defect tracking. Working closely with developers, Product managers to resolve issues and improve the product quality.

All State India: Automated web UI for Vehicle insurance. Programming Language: **JAVA;** Framework: **BDD**; CI/CD: **Jenkins**

- Involved in release testing and regression suite report analysis.
- Experience working in agile/scrum environment and working knowledge of Agile tools like JIRA.

Publicis Sapient: QA Engineer Sep 2021 – Jul 2022

Client:

Waters: Automated web UI and API for E-commerce Programming Language: JAVA, Selenium WebDriver & Rest Assured; Framework: BDD; Version Control: GIT; Agile: JIRA

- Involved in-sprint automation.
- Involved in release testing and regression suite report analysis.
- Created automation & manual tests and maintain existing test suites.

Insticator Inc.: Jr. QA Engineer Sep 2020 – Aug 2021

Automated web UI for Social Media (Commenting)
Programming Language: JAVA; Framework: BDD; CI/CD: Circle CI;
Version Control: GIT; Agile: JIRA

- Implemented automation scripts for each scenario using POM BDD framework.
- Involved in End to End toward the development of new code and reuse of existing methods & refactoring the Code.
- Identified Smoke & Regression testcases and created test suites.

CONTACT prakalpha@gmail.com +91 81108 72367 Bengaluru, KA **SKILLS JAVA** SQL **BDD Test NG** Selenium WebDriver **Rest Assured GIT JIRA** PERSONAL SKILLS Designing, Coding Manual & **Automation Testing**

Problem

Solving,

Debugging

Work Ethic,

Leadership

Sirahu Technologies: QA Engineer Nov 2018 – Mar 2020

Client:

WEX IFCS UI: Automated Web UI for Fleet card. Programming Language: **JAVA & Selenium**

WebDriver; Framework: Test NG, Hybrid; Version Control: GIT;

Test Management Tool: ALM

- Identified Smoke and Regression testcases and created test suites.
- Refactoring the Code.
- · Involved in Client Calls.
- Following Agile methodology.

Solartis Technology: QA Engineer Jan 2017 – Jul 2018

Client:

Insurance Personal Lines Product: Involved in Test planning, Test case design, Execution and defect tracking. Working closely with developers, Product managers to resolve issues and improve the product quality.

CERTIFICATION

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (2024)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (Information Technology) Aug 2012 – Apr 2016

K.L.N. College of Information Technology, Madurai